Day after day, I awake in a daze,
mezamete ha kurikaesu nemui asa ha
目覚めては繰り返す　眠い朝は
And fasten my collar tightly.
eri no tai wo kitsuku shime
襟のタイをきつく締め
As I walk through the door to my classroom,
kyoushitsu no doa kuguru to hon no sukoshi
教室のドアくぐるとほんの少し
I have the slightest bit of pride.
mune wo hatte arukidaseru
胸を張って歩き出せる
Then a wind rushed through that normal, everyday life.
sonna nichijou ni fukinukeru kaze
そんな日常に吹き抜ける風
I have a feeling I can hear it,
kikoeta ki ga shita
聞こえた気がした
I have a feeling I can sense it,
kanjita ki ga shitanda
感じた気がしたんだ
Beginning to tremble within my chest.
furuedasu ima kono mune de
震え出す今この胸で
I have a feeling it's on its way,
mou kuru ki ga shita
もう来る気がした
As the millions of stars began to disappear,
ikuoku no hoshi ga kiesatteku no wo
幾億の星が消え去ってくのを
I sent them on their way,
miokutta
見送った
Waving my hand,
te wo futta
手を振った
Whispering, "Congratulations".
yokatta ne, to
よかったね、と
OP歌詞
目覚めては繰り返す
眠い朝は
襟のタイをきつく締め
教室のドアくぐると
ほんの少し胸を張って歩き出せる
そんな日常に
吹き抜ける風
聞こえた気がした　感じた気がしたんだ
震えだす 今この胸で
もう来る気がした
幾億の星が消え去ってくのを
見送った 手を振った
良かったねと
千百次的醒來
依舊睡意沉沉的清晨
用力系緊領帶
穿過教室的大門
就能稍稍挺起胸膛 向前邁進
這樣的日常生活里
吹過的縷縷清風
似乎聽見了 似乎感觸到了
不禁顫抖 此刻我心之中
已決心要前往
幾億消失的星輝
輕揮著手 目送著它們離去
太好了呢
ED歌詞
それでも私は歩いたそれが強さだった
即便如此我仍然走了下去　這便是我的堅強
總有一天人們會變得孤身一人
．
僅僅活在在回憶之中
直到面對哪怕孤獨　我也能笑著喜歡上的那天
．
歌詞部份CrowSONG
Where... am I?
ここはどこだ
何も思い出せない
I can't remember anything.
Are you awake now?
目が覚めた
Who-
あんた
ようこそ
Welcome to...
死んで堪るか戦線へ
...the I-Ain't-Dead-Yet Battlefront.
I know this is out of the blue, but could you join our force?
唐突だけど　あなた入隊してくれないかしら
Huh? "Join"?
えっ入隊？
If you're here, then that means you're dead.
ここにいるってことは
あなた　死んだのよ
Huh?
Um, I don't really get what you me-
あの　よくわからないんだけど
This is the world of the afterlife.
ここは死んだ後の世界
If you don't act, you'll be erased.
何もしなければ消されるわよ
"Erased"?
消される？
誰に
By who?
By God, I imagine.
そりゃ神様でしょうね
Then what's this about joining your force?
じゃ入隊ってのはなに
I'm asking you to join the I-Ain't-Dead-Yet Battlefront.
死んで堪るか戦線によ
The name of the force changes often.
まぁ　部隊名はよくかわるわ
First, it was the Afterlife Battlefront.
最初は死んだ世界戦線
But that name kind of admits that you're dead, doesn't it?
でも　死んだ世界戦線って
死んだことを認めてることになるんじゃね
That's what we said.
と言うことにより破棄 以降変遷を続けてるわ
Ever since, we've been changing the name around.
Right now, we're the I-Ain't-Dead-Yet Battlefront.
今は死んで堪るか戦線
The one before that was the
It-Doesn't-Feel-Like-I'm-Alive Battlefront.
その前は生きた心地がしない戦線
ま　完全にネタだったから
Now that was a real joke, so we changed it within a day.
翻譯 夏 今矢瘋
一日で変わったけど
えぇと それって本物の銃?
Um, is that a real gun?
特效 saber 時間&後期 月染不透
Everyone who comes here has the same reaction.
ここにきたやつはみんなそんな反応するのよね
萌月諸神聯合譯製
順応性を高めなさい
Be more adaptive.
Accept things as they are.
あるがままを受け止めるの
Okay "accept," and then what happens?
受け止めって どうすればいいんだよ
You'll fight.
戦うのよ
Against what?
何と
That down there.
あれよ
あれが死んでたまるか戦線の敵
The enemy here on the
I-Ain't-Dead-Yet Battlefront.
Tenshi.
天使よ
I'd really like to hurry and change I-Ain't-Dead-Yet Battlefront to something else.
やっぱ死んで堪るか戦線はとっとと変えたいわ
You. Come up with a name.
あなた 考えておいて
Hey, hey. That's an ordinary girl there no matter how you look at it.
おいおい どう見たってあれは普通の女の子じゃないか
なに言ってんだこいつ
What's she talking about?
あのさ 向う行っていいかな
Hey, mind if I go over there?
はぁ～？
Huh?!
What for?! I don't get you!
なぜ　ワケ分からいわ
How did you come up with that?!
どうしたらそんな思考に至るの?
You must be an idiot!
あんたばかじゃないの
You should try dying once!
一遍死んだら
これは死ねないこの世界でよく使われるジョークなんだけど
By the way, that's a cliché joke in this world where no one can die.
どう？笑えるかしら？
So, was it funny?
P-Putting my thoughts on the joke aside...
ジョ ジョークの感想はいいとして
I thought I might have a better conversation with her than with a person who points a gun at a girl.
少なくとも銃を女の子に向けているような奴よりには
まともな話ができそうだからさ
私はあなたの味方よ
I'm on your side.
If you don't want me pointing guns, then I won't.
銃を向けるなと言うなら向けないわ
私を信用しなさい
Trust me.
Hey, Yurippe!
おい ゆりっぺ
What happened to recruiting the new guy?
新人勧誘の手筈はどうなってんだ？
人手が足りない今
We're short on people right now.
どんな汚い手を使ってでも…
We need to resort to every dirty trick we have-
What?
あれ
I'm going over there.
俺 向こう行くわ
うわああぁぁぁ！　勧誘に失敗した！
I failed to recruit him!
I don't get this.
訳がわからない
くそ～
What was up with them?
なんなんだアイツら
Excuse me.
あの
Ah, good evening.
こんばんわ
ええと　あんた銃で狙われてたぞ
You know, you were being targeted by a gun.
She was calling you an angel or whatnot.
あんたが天使だ とか何とか言って
I'm not an angel.
私は天使なんかじゃないわ
だよなぁ
Obviously.
じゃあ
Then-
I'm the Student Council President.
生徒会長
アホだ俺は
What an idiot I am.
あの女にからかわれてたんだ
That girl was playing around with me.
Damn it! And I don't even know who I am.
クソッ
自分が誰かもわからないし
病院にでも行くよ
I guess I'll go to the hospital or something.
There are no hospitals.
病院なんてないわよ
どうして
Why not?
Because no one gets sick.
誰も病まないから
病まないって？
"No one gets sick"?
Because we're all dead.
みんな死んでるから
Oh, I get it! You're in on this, too!
ああ わかった
お前もグルなんだな
You're trying to trick me, aren't you?
俺を騙そうとしているんだろ
Is this amnesia of mine your doing, also?
なんだ　この記憶喪失も
お前らの仕業か
記憶喪失はよくあることよ
Amnesia is a common thing here.
ここに来た時は事故死とかだったら
If someone dies in an accident, they often take a blow to the head.
頭もやられてるから
じゃあ 証明してくれよ
Then prove it!
俺は死んでるから もう死なないって…
Prove to me that I won't die since I'm already dead...
ハンドソニック
Hand Sonic.
Where is...
ここは
I'm alive...
生きてる
But it hurt so much...
あんな激痛だったのに
Damn it! Damn it! I don't understand
what's going on, but I shouldn't be here!
くっクソ
よくわかんないけど
こんなことにいちゃいらない
What's this guy's problem...
なんだこいつ
貴様か
So you're the punk who insulted Yurippe and refused to join the force?!
ゆりっぺを侮辱し　入隊を断ったという輩は
お　おい　待ってよ
Hey, hold on. Calm down.
落ち着けって
You wanna die?
死ぬか
Oh? Oh, that.
ああぁ　それね　なんだよ
You mean...
Yeah, that's hilarious.
面白いぜ
死ねない世界のおジョークなあ
That's the joke in this world where no one dies, right?
センスいいよ
Great sense of humour there.
Die a hundred times.
百遍
Die, die, die, die, die!
死ね死ね死ね…
DIE!
Insult Yurippe again, and you'll be back in the air, punk.
次ゆりっぺを侮辱したら
また舞うことになるぞ
Several Minutes Later
Are you trying to kill me?!
殺しかって
Oh, right, like that works as a come-back here...
既にツッコミがツッコミじゃねえ
At any rate, what kinda sick joke is that?!
っていうが　何がこの世界のジョークだよ
死ぬほど痛いのに死ねないなんて
It hurts like hell, yet you can't die?
最悪だ
This sucks!
ここは死んだ後の世界
This is the world of the afterlife.
何もしなければ消されるわよ
If you don't act, you'll be erased.
That's right! I'll just go and get erased!
消されればいいんだ
そうすればこんな世界からおさらばできる
Then I can get out of this world.
でも　どうすりゃいいんだ
Medical
1st Infirmary
Off-Limits
Closed
Unauthorized
Persons
B-But how exactly do I do that?
I'm on your side.
わたしはあなたの味方だよ
わたしを信用しなさい
Trust me.
Linen Room
Is there anyone who looks trustworthy out there?
どこかに信用出来そうなヤツはいねえのか
That's right!
そうだ　大人を探そう
Start by looking for an adult!
And where are the adults?
っていうか　大人はどこだよ
先生は
Any teachers?
Headmaster's Room
Maybe I'll ask the headmaster.
校長にでも聞いてみるか
そうだな　じゃこれはどうだ
Okay, how does this sound?
死ぬのはお前だ戦線
You're-the-One-Who's-Gonna-Die Battlefront.
あたしが殺されるみたいじゃない！
That sounds like I'm going to die.
No, of course we'd be targeting it at that woman.
にゃあ　勿論はあの女だ
Then look at me.
ん　どこだ？
じゃこっち見なさいよ
Where am I?
You're-the-One-Who's-Gonna-Die Battlefront.
死ぬのはお前だ戦線
Whoa, crap!
ぬう　やべー
Yeah, sounds like I'm going to get killed.
確かにに俺が殺されそうだわ
他には
Anything else?
何か案はないの
Any other suggestions?
How's this?
コレかっこよくね
走馬灯戦線
Flashback Battlefront!
You're on the verge of death.
それ死ぬ寸前じゃない！
How about this, then?
じゃこれってどうだ？
消したい戦線
Obliterate Battlefront!
You're pretty much asking to die.
死ぬのを覚悟してるじゃない！
Driven-to-the-Wall Battlefront.
絶体絶命戦線
Oh, yeah. That's right! Oh, yeah.
Death's cornering you!
絶体絶命じゃない！
How about Invincible Force?
じゃ無敵艦隊
Now we're missing the "Battlefront."
今度は戦線じゃなくなってる
Suicidal Rangers!
玉砕戦隊
Nice.
Want me to punch you?
殴るわよ！
ライト兄弟
Wright Brothers!
Shut up!
おおぎりか！もぉ　最後は戦線なのよ
I said it needs to end in "battlefront"!
That's a must, no questions!
これはゆずれないわ
We're standing on the front-line of this war.
私たちはこの戦場の第一線にいるのよ
Doesn't anyone have a better idea?
もっと増しな案はないの
ねえ　そのひともう起きてるんじゃない
Hey, isn't he awake now?
え　ああ　気がついた
Ah, so you've come to.
That's right. I told him to think up a name, too.
そうだ　コイツにも考えさせてあったのよ
You've had plenty of time.
時間はたっぷりあったわ　聞かせていただきましょうか
So let's hear it.
なによ
Hear what?
死んで堪るか戦線に代わる新しい部隊名よ
A new team name that will replace the I-Ain't-Dead-Yet Battlefront.
勝手にやってろう戦線
I-Don't-Care Battlefront.
ほお　ゆりっぺに歯向かうとはいい度胸じゃないか
You got some real nerve to defy Yurippe.
I said I don't care what you guys do!
勝手にやってろうって言ってんだよ
What did you say?!
んだと？
なんだよ　お前ら　俺を巻き込むなよ
What are you guys?!
Don't drag me into this!
俺はとっとと消えるんだ
I'm going to go and get erased!
You want to disappear? Even though you exist here?
消えたい　今ここに存在しているのにですか
Yeah, that's right!
ああ　そうだよ
I already explained that bit to him.
その説明はしたわ
抗いもせず消されることを望むと
So you wish to disappear without even putting up a fight?
ああ
Yeah!
So you choose to turn into a water flea without even putting up a fight?
抗いもせずミジンコになると
Yeah!
ああ　はあ　ミジンコ
What? "Water flea"?
ふん魂が人間だけに宿るもんとでも思ってたのかよてめぇ
You thought only humans have souls, punk?
How unwise.
浅はかなり
つぎは藤壺かもしれん
You might even turn into a barnacle next time.
やどかりかもしれん
Or maybe a hermit crab.
船虫であるかもしれん
Or even a wharf roach!
はあ　そんあまさか
You've gotta be kidding!
なぜ浜辺に集住してるのかと
And you're not even asking why the
choice is limited to aquatic creatures.
つっ込む余裕もなさそうな顔ですね
ちなみに意味なんてありません
For the record, there is no reason.
So, come on. Get outta here, already.
おら　とっととここから出ていけよ
天使のいいなりになって　無事成仏するんだろ
You're gonna become Tenshi's pet and go "rest in peace," right?
Go become a barnacle and get eaten by humans, already.
藤壺になって人間に食われてもすんだら
Wouldn't that be such a pleasant new life?
幸せな来世じゃねえか
A barnacle...
藤壺
What? Barnacles are edible?
えい一　藤壺って食べられるの
There are some that are edible.
食用のものもあります
知らなかったぜ
I never knew that.
How unwise.
浅はかなり
まあ　まあ　みんな
Easy now, everyone.
そんな追い出すようなマネはしないであげなさい
Don't be so mean and force him out.
The poor thing.
可哀そうに
We the...
このわが　あぁ　ええと　今なんだっけ
Um... what were we right now, again?
Barnacle Battlefront.
藤壺戦線
Right! We of the Barnacle Battlefront will-
そう　このわが藤壺
Headmaster's Room
元に戻す　死んだ世界戦線
I'm reverting it!
We're the Afterlife Battlefront!
That was a good kick.
いい蹴りだったぜ
While you remain in the Battlefront's Headquarters here, you're safe.
この戦線の本部にいる間は安全なんだから
You came here knowing that, didn't you?
かれもそれを知って逃げ込んできたんでしょ
いや　知らないし
No, I didn't.
入ろうとした途端　吹っ飛ばれたし
Besides, the moment I tried to enter, I was knocked away.
っていうか来世あったとして
But anyway, assuming that there really is reincarnation, you're just joking about not being human, right?
人間じゃないかもしれないなんて
冗談だろ
We're not joking.
冗談ではない
だってそんなの確かなれないじゃないか
How would one confirm such a thing?
誰が見てきたのよ
Has anyone seen it themselves?
そりゃ確かめられないわよ
Of course they haven't!
でも仏教では人に生まれ変わると限らないと考えられてるわ
But in Buddhism, it's thought possible to
reincarnate into something other than a human.
そんな藤壺だ　なんて
But still... a barnacle?
Well, religions are all created by humans, but listen closely.
まあ　宗教なんて人間の考えたものなんだけど　でもね
よく聞きなさい　ここが大事よ
This is the important part.
In the world where we once lived,
death came indiscriminately and randomly.
アタシたちがかつて生きていた世界では人の死は無差別に
無作為に訪れるものだった
だから抗いようもなかった
As such, there was no way for us to fight against it.
でもこの世界は違うのよ
But that's not true in this world.
You can continue to survive as long as you keep fighting against Tenshi.
天使にさえ抵抗すれば存在し続けられる
You can rebel!
抗えるのよ
But wait, what lies beyond that?
でも　待って
その先にあるのは何なんだ
お前らは何をしたいんだ
What do you all hope to accomplish?
Our objective is to obliterate Tenshi.
私たちの目的は天使を消し去ること
そしてこの世界を手に入れる
And to seize this world!
You've only just arrived, so it's no surprise that you're totally confused.
まだ来て間もないから　混乱するのも無理ないわ
順応性を高めなさい　そしてあるがままを受け止めなさい
Be more adaptive.
Just accept things as they are.
So we fight? Against Tenshi?
そして戦うのか　天使と
そうよ　共にね
That's right.
Together.
早まるな！ゆりっ！
Not so fast, Yurip-
What an idiot.
アホだ　自分の仕掛けた罠にはまってやがれ
He fell for the trap he set himself.
So that's what I looked like, too.
俺もああなってたのか
ここに無事に入るには合言葉が必要なのよ
To enter here safely, you need a pass phrase.
Headmaster's Room
「対天使用の作戦本部」というわけ
This is the Headquarters for anti-Tenshi forces.
ここ以外に安全に話し合える場所などないわ
There are no other places we can talk safely.
Could you give me some time?
すこしじかんをくれないか
ここ以外でならどうぞ
Sure, as long as you spend it here.
Fine, I'll join!
オーケーだ
What's the pass phrase?
合言葉は？
「神も仏も天使もなし」
"No God, no Buddha, nor angels exist."
わたしはゆり　この戦線のリーダーよ
I'm Yuri.
I'm the leader on this battlefront.
He's Hinata-kun.
で　彼は日向君　見た目どおりちゃらんぽらんだけど
As you can see, he's quite lax, but he'll do what's necessary at times.
やる時はたまにやるわ
Hi-
って　フォローになってないぜ
Hey, you're not giving me enough credit!
He's Matsushita-kun.
彼は松下君柔道五段だから
無視かよ
Totally ignoring me...
He's a fifth degree black belt in judo,
敬意を持って　みんなは松下五段と呼ぶわ
so everyone calls him Matsushita Fifth, with respect.
Nice to meet you.
よろしくな
彼は大山君　特徴がないのが特徴よ
He's Ooyama-kun.
His lack of character is his defining characteristic.
Welcome to the Battlefront.
ようこそ　戦線へ
C'mon , let's dance!
カムオンレッツダンス
ああいや　踊らねえけど
No, I don't think I will.
Okay... don't be afraid.
That's his way of saying hello.
この人なりの挨拶よ　みんなTKと呼んでるわ
Feel the groove, man.
Everyone calls him T.K.
本名は誰も知らない謎の男よ
He's a mystery man. No one knows his real name.
Yeah, nice and slow.
Are you sure about keeping someone like that as an ally?
Yeah, step on!
そんなやつが仲間でいいんのか
眼鏡をいちいち持ち上げて知的に話すのは高松君
The one who's always straightening his glasses to look smart is Takamatsu-kun.
本当は馬鹿よ
He's actually an idiot.
Pleased to meet you.
よろしく
後彼が藤巻君
And he's Fujimaki-kun.
藤巻だ　坊主
Remember, it's Fujimaki, you brat.
坊主じゃない
I'm not a brat.
で　先飛んでいたのは野田君
Oh, and the one who flew out just now is Noda-kun.
The one who keeps saying "How unwise" is Shiina-san.
陰で浅いはかなりって言い続けてるのは椎名さん
こっちに座ってるのは岩沢さん
And the one sitting here is Iwasawa-san.
She's the leader of the Diversion Division.
誘導部隊のリーダー
Besides us, there are dozens of other...
後ここにいないだけど
...Battlefront members within the school.
戦線のメンバーはまだ何十人と校内で潜伏してるわ
Well, let's see.
Come to think of it, what's your name?
そういえば　あなた名前は？
Huh? Oh, um...
O-Oto...
お　音無
...Otonashi.
What's your given name?
下は？
I can't remember.
思い出せねえ
Ah, it's amnesia.
記憶がないパタンか
Don't worry!
安心しろう　じきに戻るさ
You'll remember things soon enough.
Hey, shouldn't you give him the school uniform?
おい　制服は渡せなくていいのか
Oh yeah, I forgot.
あそうね
忘れてた
Right...
そういえば　何でオレは
Why is my uniform different from everyone else's?
その　お前たちとは違うんだ
It's not that you're any different.
あんたが違うんじゃないわ
We are different.
私たちが違うのよ
You're dressed in what honour students wear.
それは模範生の格好
Whereas what we wear are the SSS uniforms.
TL Note: The SSS, short for Shinda Sekai Sensen, aka the Afterlife Battlefront.
これが私達　クラスSSSの格好ってわけ
Rooftop
Classroom Building A
This is a pretty big school.
でっかい学園だな
教學樓A棟　屋頂
そう生徒数二千人強
A little over two thousand students.
全寮制のマンモス校よ
It's a mammoth all-boarding school.
I don't know who-
いったいどこの誰か
Hey, is it all right to be talking at a place like this?
な　こんなところで話して大丈夫なのか
Yeah, so long as it's not battle plans.
あ　作戦の話以外ならね
だまされた気分だ
I feel like I've been tricked.
What?
なに
Nothing.
いや
Hey, is that canned coffee?
で　それ　缶コーヒーか
キーコーヒ　おいしいわよ
It's Key Coffee. It's good, you know?
それが質問？
That's what you wanted to ask?
ああ　いや
Ah, well...
あいつらは
Who are they?
いまは部活やら帰宅やらの真最中ね
Right now is when people are either busy with clubs or heading home.
You guys don't do either?
おまえらはやらないのか
そんなことしたら　消えちゃうじゃない
We'll disappear, if we do.
We humans would disappear if we participate in clubs, as Tenshi says.
天使の言いなりになって
授業や部活を受けると
私達人は消えちゃうの
"Humans"?
人は？
まるであいつらは人じゃないみたい言い方だな
From how you talk, sounds like they're not human.
Let's go grab some food.
You're right. They're NPCs.
そのとおり
かれらはエヌピーシーよ
エヌピーシー?
"NPCs"?
知らない？
You've never heard? It stands for non-player character.
ノン　プレイヤー　キャラクター
Are you talking about a game world?
ゲームの話か
It's just an example.
たとえよ　連中はこの世界に最初からいる模範って意味
They're honour students who exist in this world to begin with.
なら自意識はないのか
Then they don't have any self-awareness?
話しかけても同じ答えしか返てこないとか？
Would they only return the same answer no matter how many times we talk to them?
Try it for yourself.
試してみたら？
始めてばかりのあなたには
As a newcomer to this world, it can be hard to tell the difference between us and them.
私達との違いは見抜けないと思うわ
あ　会話が成り立つのか
So we can actually converse with them?
女の子にいきなりカンチョーしてみなさいよ
拜觀音（カンチョー）:雙手食指豎起合在一起其他手指收攏，然後插臀部
Go and kancho a girl.
TL Note: Kancho is a Japanese slang word to describe a prank involving the attempted insertion of a finger into another person's anal region.
カンチョー？
Kancho?!
She'll either run away or you'll get kicked.
逃げるか蹴られるかするわよ
S-So they're well-made...
よ　よくできてんだな
And the teachers?
先生もか
そう　ちなみにNPCは年をとらない
The same. And just so you know, NPCs never age.
それは私達も同じ
That applies to us, too.
ほかには
Any other questions?
天使の凶暴性は
How violent is Tenshi?
俺は出会って　すぐ刺された
She stabbed me the moment we met.
見てだけど
I was watching, but really, you brought that upon yourself.
あれはあなたの自爆じゃない
「死なないことを証明しろう」だなんて天使にお願いしたら
If you ask Tenshi to prove that you can't die,
そりゃ心臓一突きにされちゃうわよ
then of course she'll skewer you right through your heart.
彼女すれば
To her, that was no different than answering where the Faculty Lounge is.
職員室の場所を聞かれて答えるのと同じことだよ
So Tenshi strictly obeys this world's rules.
天使にはこの世界のルールには従順ということか
不器用ってことよ
She's just clumsy.
自意識があるのか
She has self-awareness?
さあね　謎
Dunno. It's a mystery.
無感情無愛想　言葉数が少な過ぎる点ではNPCより個性的ね
How she's emotionless, unsociable, and speaks
minimally makes her unique compared to NPCs.
じゃ普通はあんな簡単に殺され…
So normally, we aren't killed-
Well, aren't beaten so easily.
いや　やられたりすることはないのか
Those who don't fit themselves to the honour
student role will first be given a verbal warning.
「模範どおり」に構内活動行わない生徒に対しては
まず口頭注意
逃げれば追ってくるし　先回りして行く手を阻む
If you run away, she'll chase you and even get in your way.
実力行使?
Does it ever get physical?
Eye for an eye!
目には目を　こっちが仕掛けた時はね
Only when we start the fight, though.
So there are times when you'll get beaten up like I did.
オレの様にやられることもあるっと
Of course.
もちろん　後「模範どおり」にはふりだけでもしないことね
And you shouldn't even pretend to be an honour student.
There are those who have disappeared because of that.
それで消えたやつもいるわ
わかったじゃ最後
Okay. Then here's the last question.
神についてた　存在するのか
Regarding God.
Does He exist?
I believe in Him, though I've haven't met Him, yet.
私は信じるわ　まだみたことはないけど
天使に聞いてみたことはないのか
You've never asked Tenshi about it?
この世界の根幹に関すること質問にはノーコメントみたいよ
She doesn't answer questions that touch upon the foundations of this world.
And that concludes Lecture Hour.
以上　お勉強会は終了ね
To be honest, I haven't united with them, yet.
正直なところ　オレは団結なんかしていない
今俺は最も優先すべきもの
What I should be focusing on now is to buy
the time necessary to get my memory back.
それは自分の記憶を取り戻すまでの時間を無事に稼ぐこと
それだけだ
That's all.
After that!
それからは　それからは…
After that...
わからない
...I don't know.
Anti-Tenshi Operation HQ
對天使用作戰本部
はい 音無君
Here, Otonashi-kun.
This should work, even if it's your first time.
はじめてでも打てるわ
効くのか
Is it effective?
Aim for her foot. That'll at least stop her from chasing after you.
足を狙いなさい　とりあえず追ってこなくなるわ
Firing a gun on a girl?
女の子相手にか
傷はすぐに癒えるのか
Will the wound heal fast?
そういうのは経験して覚えていきなさい
You should learn those things through experience.
私達はそうしてきたんだから
That's how we learned.
いいだろう
Fine.
いい返事ね　音無君
Good answer, Otonashi-kun.
To get you started and familiar with your surroundings,
まずあなたには慣れてもらうために
いつもやっている簡単な作戦に参加してもらうわ
I'll have you take part in the daily operation.
作戦名　オぺレーション　トルネード
Code name: Operation Tornado.
こいつはでかいのが来たな
Ah, this is big.
"T-Tornado"?
ト　トルネード
We'll sweep away lunch tickets from the students!
生徒から食券件を巻き上げる
その巻き上げるかよ
That's what you meant by "tornado"?!
しかもでかくねーよ　いじめかよ
And that's not big at all! It's just simple bullying!
失望したぜ　武器や頭数だけ揃いあがってよ
I've totally lost faith in you guys! All you have are weapons and numbers!
You punk! That's an insult to Yurippe.
きさま！これはゆりっぺに対するな侮辱発言だ
I'll have you take that back.
撤回してもらおうか
Why?!
なんてだよ
We of the Barnacle-Extinction-Prevention Battlefront
would never threaten students with numbers or violence.
われら「藤壺絶滅保護戦線」は
数や力で一般生徒を脅かすようなまねなど決してしない
They're on the verge of extinction?!
あれ絶滅するの
I'm sure they will be someday.
いつかはするだろう
But you just said you're sweeping them away!
でも巻き上げるって言ってだろうか
Yes, and we will, literally.
ええ　文字通り巻き上げるわ
いい　あなたは天使の進行を阻止するバリケード班
Listen. You'll be part of the barricade
group that will inhibit Tenshi's interference.
School Cafeteria
Hinata
2 Guides
Fujimaki
Noda
Takamatsu
1 Spotter
Ooyama
Matsushita
Shiina
作戦ポイントである食堂を取り囲むように
You'll be on standby with a weapon at designated
locations around the cafeteria, the area of operations.
Fujimaki
Noda
Matsushita
1 Spotter
Shiina
School Cafeteria
Ooyama
それぞれ指定のポジションで武装待機
School Cafeteria
Ooyama
Noda
2 Guides
Hinata
1 Spotter
Takamatsu
Fujimaki
Shiina
安心しなさい　楽なところにおいてあげる
And relax, I'll drop you at an easy point.
Ask for details from Takamatsu-kun or Ooyama-kun later.
細かい位置は　あとで高松君か大山君に確認して
岩沢さん　今日も期待してるわ
Iwasawa-san, I look forward to a good performance, too.
あ
Yeah.
天使が現れたら各自開砲
When Tenshi appears, open fire.
それが増援要請の合図になるわ
That will be the signal to request reinforcements.
どこかで銃声が聞こえたら　あなたも駆けつけるように
If you hear gunfire, you go running there, too.
作線開始時刻は　一八三○
The operation start time is 18:30.
Operation Start Time
Estimated Operation Finish Time
Current Time
Estimated Live Concert Finish Time
Operation Start Time
Estimated Operation Finish Time
Current Time
Estimated Live Concert Finish Time
Operation Start Time
Estimated Operation Finish Time
Current Time
Estimated Live Concert Finish Time
オペレーション　スタート！
Operation start!
School Cafeteria
學園大食堂
Second Bridge
第二聯絡橋
この作戦でいったいどうやって
How's this operation going to peacefully sweep away lunch tickets?
食券を平和的に巻き上げるんだ
School Cafeteria Interior
こちら遊佐です　照明班　音響班　主にスタンバイ完了
This is Yusa.
學園大食堂　內部
The lighting and sound staff are on standby.
そろそろ頃合かと
I believe it's about time.
気がついたファンを集ってきています
The fans are starting to gather.
Okay.
オーケー
So, shall we get started?
じゃ　はじまるとするか
背後にはシャッターの壁
Behind me is a wall of shutters flashing,
haigo ni ha shatta- no kabe
背後にはシャッターの壁
Hey, it's GirlDeMo!
おい　ガルデモだ！
The live concert's started!
ライブはじまったよ
指先は鉄の匂い
And the tips of my fingers smell of metal.
yubisaki ha tetsu no niyoi
指先は鉄の匂い
つぶれ弾け
I'll go bounding forward,
susume hajike
進め弾け
どの道混むでしょ
And weave through each and every pathway.
dono michi komu desho
どのみち混むでしょ
Crow way ここから
Find a way, away from here,
find a way koko kara
ここから
Calｍ dawn　見つける
Found out, I'll discover it,
found out mitsukeru
見つける
Ｒockを奏でろ
Play the rock out loud,
rock wo kanadero
を奏でろ
遠くを見据えろ
Gaze into the distance,
tooku wo misuero
遠くを見据えろ
息継ぎさえ出来ない街の中
From a city in which we're too cramped to breathe.
ikitsugi sae dekinai machi no naka
息継ぎさえできない町の中
星空が最高の舞台
A star-filled sky is the greatest stage,
hoshizora ga saikou no butai
星空が最高の舞台
カラスだってカーカーと鳴くよ
And all the crows are crying, "caw- caw-".
karasutachi ka- ka- to naku yo
カラスたちカーカーと鳴くよ
現れた
She's there.
She's right there.
現われやがた
She's right in front of me.
オレのところに　今の戦線無弱点だよ
いつも向こうを見つめてるんだろ
So I'm the weakest link on the current battlefront, eh?
I'm always wondering,
itsumo omou yo
いつも思うよ
完全に見縊られてる
She's totally underestimating me.
When will I ever sleep.
itsu neterundaro
いつ寝てるんだろ
くそう　うってやる
Damn it! I'll shoot!
Crow way　私も
I'll find my own way,
find a way atashi mo
あたしも
でも　あんなきゃしゃな体を銃弾でか
But, if a bullet goes through that frail body...
Crow song 歌うよ
I'll sing a song for you,
song for utau yo
歌うよ
If I don't shoot, she'll get me.
やらなきゃ　やられるんだ
She won't show any mercy.
何の容赦もなく
Ｒockを響かせ
Make the rock resound,
rock wo hibikase
を響かせ
It hit!
当たった
And sing with the crows.
crow to utau yo
と歌うよ
Ｌove　Song　歌うよ
そんな　足でよかったのに
But, the leg was all I needed to hit.
もう十分じゃないか　もう…
That's enough...
"Just how long do you plan to stay here?"
itsu made konna tokoro ni iru?
いつまでこんなところに居る？
何時まで　そんなところにいる
It's...
Guard Skill: Hand Sonic.
「ガードスキル　ハンドソニック」
そういう奴じゃなかった気がする
I remember someone here asking me that.
sou iu yatsu mo ita ki ga suru
そう言う奴もいた気がする
うるさいことだけ言うのなら
If all you're going to say is that annoying crap,
urusai koto dake iu no nara
うるさいことだけ言うのなら
そんな　そんな
No way... No way!
漆黒の羽に攫われて
Get carried away in a flurry of jet-black wings.
shikkoku no hane ni sarawarete kietekure
漆黒の羽にさらわれて消えてくれ
Why? Why won't she stop?!
どうしたよ　どうした止まらない
消えてくれ
W-What's that supposed to be?!
なんだよそれ
Damn it!
くそ
Crap, I missed.
はずしたか
Sorry to make you wait.
待たせたな
Give you a little kiss!
Get your little kiss
一番弱ぇとこ狙われたんじゃねーか
I'd say she came after the weakest link, yo!
She's only using Hand Sonic right now.
まだハンドソッニクだけだよ
すぐ行く　でも高い空
I'm running at full speed and about to collapse,
zenryoku de mou taoresouda
全力でもう倒れそうだ
広い場所へ
Head to a place that's more open!
後退しながら　加重攻撃
We'll fire as we fall back!
Roger.
了解
Ready?
いくぞ
いつも擦り切れていたり
And my fingers hurt from being rubbed raw.
yobi mo surikirete itai
指もすり切れて痛い
「ガード　スキル　ディストーション」
Guard Skill: Distortion.
Fire!
打て
But I'll do it,
demo ne yaru yo
でもね　演るよ
見つめあうよ　運命見せてよ
Tonight will be a big story.
konya mo niggu na sto-ri-
今夜もビッグなストーリー
God damn it!
くそ　おそかったか
We were too late.
My God!
これだから銃は
This is why I hate guns!
Crow way ここから
Find a way, away from here,
find a way koko kara
ここから
Calｍ dawn　見つける
Found out, I'll discover it,
found out mitsukeru
見つける
Ｒockを奏でろ
Play the rock out loud,
rock wo kanadero
を奏でろ
Ｌove　Song歌うよ
I'll sing my luck.
luck wo utauyo
を歌うよ
いつまでだって此処にいるよ
I'll always be here,
itsumade datte koko ni iru yo
いつまでだってここに居るよ
通り過ぎてゆく人の中
Among the people that come and go.
toorisugiteyuku hito no naka
通り過ぎてゆく人の中
God damn!
くそ　ってなんかよ巻き上げは
What's taking the tornado so long?!
闇に閉ざされたステージで
On a stage closed off by darkness,
yami ni tozasareta sute-ji de
闇に閉ざされたステージで
I never thought buying time would
end up meaning something like this.
時間稼ぎだ　まさかこんな壮絶ことになるなんて
I'll sing a song of hope.
ima kibou no uta utau yo
今希望の詩歌うよ
いま希望の歌を歌いたい
あなただって疲れてるでしょ
Even you are probably tired by now,
anata datte tsukareteru desho
あなただって疲れてるでしょ
その背中にも届けたいよ
I'll send my song to your aching back.
sono senaka ni mo todoketai yo
その背中にも届けたいよ
こんな暗闇の中からも
Seems we're at the climax.
From this very darkness,
konna kurayami no naka kara no
こんな暗闇の中からの
煙雲駆け回ったな
Spin it.
回せ
希望照らす光の歌を
Take this song that shines of hope,
kibou terasu hikari no uta wo
希望照らす光の歌を
回してください
Spin it, please.
その歌を
Take this song.
sono uta wo
その歌を
Beef Udon
School Cafeteria
Food Court
（肉烏冬）
That what you want? Let's go!
それでいいんのか　いくぞ
Here's your beef udon.
はいよ　肉うどん　お待ち
Mmm, this is so delicious.
Oh, yeah.
Is it all right for us to be eating here so carelessly?
いいのかこんなところでのんきに食ったら
あいつは襲ってこないのか
Won't she come after us?
We're only eating.
ただご飯食べてるだけじゃない
そういうもんのか
So that's how it works, huh?
いつも一人で歩いてた
總是一人孤單地走著
I've always walked this path alone; when I look back, everyone is so far away.
itsumo hitori de aruiteta furikaeru to minna ha tooku
これだけ統率力と力があれば
With this much insight and power,
they should be capable of doing anything.
何だってし放題なのに
こんな地味に召し食って暮らしてんのか
And yet, they're leading a plain life
right now, eating like everyone else.
Could you pass me the pepper?
振り返るとみんなは遠く
暮然回首才發現人們都已經遠去了
Here.
There's really only one enemy.
敵は本当にたったてひとり
天使だけなんだ
Just Tenshi.
あいつと戦ってるだけなんだ
They're really only fighting against her.
"Nothing frightens me any longer", I mumble softly.
mou nanimo kowakunai sou tsubuyaitemiseru
もう何も 怖くない
已經沒有什麽好怕的了
でも　正当化するのか　その行為を
But, will I somehow justify this behaviour?
いや　まだ早い
No. It's too early for that.
そうつぶやいてみせる
我在你身邊這樣輕輕説著
オレには　記憶がないんだから
After all...
...I don't remember anything.
Eventually, everyone ends up alone,
itsuka hito ha hitori ni natte
いつか人は一人になって
いつか　人は一人になって
總有一天人們會變得孤身一人
And is left with only their memories.
omoide no naka ni ikiteku dake
思い出の中に生きてくだけ
僅僅活在在回憶之中
In order to appreciate even sorrow and continue smiling,
kodoku sae aishi waratterareru you ni
孤独さえ愛し笑ってられるように
直到面對哪怕孤獨　我也能笑著喜歡上的那天
I'll keep on fighting,
atashi ha tatakaunda
あたしは戦うんだ
私は戦うんだ
我要戰鬥到底
I won't show you my tears.
namida nante misenainda
涙なんて見せないんだ
絶不讓你看到我落淚
Next Episode Preview
Parachute operation...
We call it The Guild.
You're gonna be next.
Run for it!
It seems you still do not understand.
The traps weren't disarmed?!
Shoot, I forgot!
Because I was the first to rebel.
I don't know... I don't know of anything like that!
Tenshi's getting up!
Fire!!
What the heck am I doing?
I can't forgive being given such a life.